# Ross M. Higley

801-674-7812 810 Ayer st. Fruitland, ID 83619 higleyross@gmail.com http://lnkd.in/PVRWRM

# **Personal Summary**

As a Teacher's Assistant in the Business Information Systems Program, designed, built and implemented 60 computer images per semester. Without these computer images the class could not have functioned. Designed and documented 10 different lab troubleshooting scenarios for use as the course final test. As a result more than 30 students were able to pass their classes. Certifications in Windows Operating Systems and experience with Java, HTML5, and CSS3.

# Experience

**Lamb Weston** 

June 2014 – July 2014

Package Utility

American Falls, ID

Ensured quality of packaging for over 2000 thirty pound boxes a day.

Operated machinery including: case erectors, glue presses, and case settlers.

Stacked thirty pound boxes onto pallets, 63 boxes per pallet, by hand.

Convergys

May 2013 – Dec 2013

Customer Service & Problem Resolution Representative II

Murray, UT

Resolved technical and billing issues from over 25 clients per day.

Explained billing inquiries in an easy to understand manner.

Assisted clients to find packages that both fulfill their needs and fit their budgets.

#### LDS Business College

Jan 2013 – May 2013

Teacher's Assistant

Salt Lake City, UT

Designed and helped teach course IS 181 Windows 7 Configuration.

Coordinated with the Teacher and IT department to prepare the computer lab.

Built and implemented 60 computer images for students' coursework.

Wrote and distributed errata for lab manuals.

Designed and documented 10 lab troubleshooting scenarios for course final test.

#### **LDS Business College**

Jan 2013 – May 2013

**Business Information Systems Tutor** 

Salt Lake City, UT

Tutored students to certify in MCTS 70-680 Windows 7 Configuration.

Tutored students to certify in MCTS 70-640 Windows Server 2008 Configuration.

Worked with Students to improve skills, understanding and morale.

Certified for tutoring by College Reading and Learning Association (CRLA).

#### The Berry Ranch

Aug 2011 – Oct 2011

General Farm Hand

Nampa, ID

Acted as Assistant to Yard Boss.

Fulfilled invoices by loading 54 pallet-bins onto a truck per day.

Measured and ensured correct product weight for produce orders.

Expanded horizons by learning to drive forklifts, tractors, and ATVs.

#### HJ Heinz

June 2011 – Aug 2011

**Production Worker** 

Ontario, OR

Processed and sorted hundreds of thousands of potatoes per day.

Assumed the responsibility and workload of absent fellow employees.

Coordinated with line boss to fill the most needed positions.

Maintained the cleanliness and productivity of the factory daily.

# **Wayne Ashton**

May 2009 – July 2011

Personal Assistant

Fruitland, ID

Performed yard maintenance and weeded garden.

Enhanced landscape by repairing and installing bricks and tiles.

Managed, repaired, and installed sprinklers, irrigation pipes, and electric fencing.

### Achievements

# **Boy Scouts of America**

Dec 2008

Eagle Scout Award

Fruitland, ID

Coordinated the planting of over 300 desert shrubs and grasses in front of the new Fruitland Elementary School Building.

Managed and recorded the hours of over 30 people in the 225 total hour project.

Coordinated with Fruitland School District to ensure quality of work.

#### Education

#### **LDS Business College**

Dec 2014

Information Technology Associate of Applied Science

Salt Lake City, UT

Emphasis in Database, Network, and Server Administration.

Database Management through Microsoft Access and Microsoft SQL Server.

Certified in MTA 98-349 Windows OS Fundamentals.

Proficient with Java7, T-SQL, HTML5 and CSS3.

Source Code available at http://Deedsogado.github.io.